Amell Ortiz

Scarborough (Ontario), M1C 3S4.

647-928-2987

ortiz.amell@gmail.com

Responsible, dedicated, hard-working and organized professional with a 14-years career in Technology and Human Resources; Certified as ITIL 4, Scrum Master and Product Owner. Efficient working on several projects simultaneously and with the ability to work under pressure and adapt to new situations and challenges to achieve the company's objectives.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Technician

Centennial College, September 2022 - Present

Master's Degree in Industrial Engineering

APEC University, August 2018 – August 2021

Bachelor's Degree in Business Administration

APEC University, January 2009 - September 2015

Technician in Informatics

POMAVID, August 2006 - July 2008

OTHER COURSES / CERTIFICATIONS

Certificate Technical Support Fundamentals - Google, August 2022

Certified ITIL 4 - PeopleCert, January 2022

Certified Scrum Product Owner - SPOPC - CertiProf, December 2021

Certified Scrum Master - SMPC - CertiProf, November 2021

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IT Monitoring Analyst - Real Estate Registry, January 2022 - October 2022

- Supervised and controlled the performance of the projects, ensuring that the deliverables were met by more than 95%.
- Supported the team to achieve defined operating benefits for our area.
- Property performance reports of the work carried out by the team to present to management.

Compensation and Benefits Analyst - Real Estate Registry,

November 2020 - December 2021

- Coordinated payroll payment process for more than one thousand employees.
- Recorded employee updates in the system (change of roles, salaries, location, etc.).
- Managed employee benefits program established by the company.

Material Requirements Planning (MRP) - Nestle, November 2019 - June 2020

- Led planning process for Raw materials available in the factory.
- Managed Supply of Raw Materials and followed up on the accuracy of inventory on hand.
- Owned the management of claims related to raw materials and suppliers' performance.

Business Solution Specialist - Nestle, October 2017 - November 2019

- Leader of programs and projects in the area to improve the service received by employees.
- Provide permissions to users to the SAP system (access that employees had to the system).
- Managed the process and monitoring of KPIs to improve the service and present the results to management.

Bank Office Sub Manager - BHD Bank, September 2016 - October 2017

- User access enabled to Internet Banking, so that they can navigate the platform and carry out transactions.
- Creation of users to companies and facilitation of permits to transact on the platform.
- Support the areas of Personal Banking and Business Banking so that customers receive a faster response.

Human Resources - BHD Bank, September 2011 - September 2016

- Recruitment and selection of personnel in the business and technology areas.
- Process changes of employees in the system (change of salaries, location, etc.).
- Provide references of former employees of the institution.
- Conduct exit interviews of employees resigning from the company.
- Correct employee performance appraisals and submit results to supervisors.
- Execute employee outputs in the system.

Sales Supervisor - Chef Products, January 2011 - September 2011

- Supervised a team of 11 salespeople and 2 merchandisers.
- Managed the monthly sales budget to ensure compliance with it.

Technical support - PetroQuim Industries, July 2008 - October 2010

- In charge of managing, supplying and installing the hardware that users needed.
- Installation and maintenance of software for more than 300 employees.
- Prepare and install network cables.

SKILLS

- Languages: Spanish (native) / English

- Scrum

- ITIL 4

- IT Project

- HTML

- MS Office

- SAP / AS 400

- Windows / Mac / Linux

- Technician Support

- .Net (C#)